Guide to the Franz R. and Kathryn M. Stenzel Collection of Western American Art
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Other Artwork, 1790-1966; Series IV; 24.06; (15 boxes)
  - BELL-SMITH, FREDERICK MARLETT
    - "A Glacier Cascade." Watercolor, 51.4 x 33.9 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 628)
  - BERGSTROM, [----?]
    - "Matthew Peasley [and] Vigilant, Last Sailboat to take Cargo from Vancouver." Oil painting on masonite, 50.8 x 40.8 cm. (Box 33, Folder 629)
  - BERNINGHAUS, OSCAR E. (OSCAR EDMUND)
    - "Attack on an Emigrant Train." Chromolithograph, 28.9 x 50.8 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 630)
      "Copyright by August A. Busch"
    - "The Father of Waters." Chromolithograph, 28.7 x 50.9 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 631)
    - "A Fight for the Overland Mail." Chromolithograph, 29 x 50.8 cm. (Box 33, Folder 632)
      "Copyright by Anheuser-Busch Brewing Assn. St. Louis, U.S.A."
    - "The Relief Train." Chromolithograph, 28.9 x 50.8 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 633)
      "Copyright by Anheuser-Busch Brewing Assn. St. Louis U.S.A."
    - "Westward Ho!" Chromolithograph, 28.9 x 50.8 cm., n.d. (Box 33, Folder 634)
  - BILL, HENRY
    - "The First Battle Between 'Iron' Ships of War." Chromolithograph, 37.6 x 49.5 cm. (Box 34, Folder 635)
      Caption continues: "The 'Monitor' 2 Guns and 'Merrimac' 10 Guns. The Merrimac was crippled and the whole Rebel Fleet driven off."
  - BINGHAM, GEORGE E.
    - "Madison Street Bridge." Pen-and-ink drawing, 28.6 x 36.2 cm., 1911 Mar 16 (Box 34, Folder 636)
  - BLOOMER, [----?]
    - [Landscape with figure in red, sailboats on lake, mountain in distance.] Oil painting, 10.9 x 20.1 cm. (Box 34, Folder 637)
  - BODMER, KARL
    - "Fort Union on the Missouri." Two color halftones, 43.1 x 60.2 cm., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 638)
      "Coblenz bei J. Hölscher. London: Ackermann & Co. Paris: Arthur Bertrand." Two copies
  - BOEHM, H. RICHARD
    - "At last they were afloat on the Ohio, bound into the unknown country, that lay far away to the westward." Watercolor, 42.2 x 26.9 cm. (Box 34, Folder 639)
      Signed. Illustration for Chapter 12, page 58 of Pioneer Boys of the Mississippi by Harrison Adams
    - "The watching boys saw him suddenly raise up as though on his knees and they could plainly discern the figure under the wolfskin now." Watercolor, 42.4 x 26.9 cm. (Box 34, Folder 640)
      Signed. Illustration for Chapter 21, page 96 of Pioneer Boys of the Mississippi by Harrison Adams
  - [BORG, CARL OSCAR?]
    - [Native American on horseback with packhorse.] Oil painting, 11.0 x 14 cm. in frame 28.2 x 33.3 cm., n.d.
      Signed "B.O.B." [possibly C.O.B., as Stenzel notes indicate. Title from Stenzel notes]
  - BRUSH, GEORGE DE FOREST
    - "Before the Battle." Photogravure, 21.7 x 35.2 cm. on sheet 31.8 x 42.2 cm., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 641)
      "Photogravure Goupil & Co. D. Appleton & Co. New York"
  - BURR, ALFRED B.
    - See also: Alfred B. Burr's work in Series V, box 51, folder 1007
    - "Oregon - The Million Dollar Union Depot Under Construction at Portland." Chromolithograph, 33.5 x 49.5 cm. (Box 34, Folder 642)
  - BUTTRE, J. C.
    - "Lieut. Genl. Ulysses S. Grant, U.S.A." Engraving and etching, 42.8 x 32.9 cm., 1864 (Box 34, Folder 643)
      "Photograph by Barr & Young. Engraved by J. C. Buttre, N.Y. Published by Ledyard Bill, New York"
  - BYXBE, LYMAN
    - "Cheyenne." Etching, plate mark 18.5 x 12 cm. on sheet 29.8 x 21.5 cm., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 644)
  - C., J.
    - "A Close Finish." Pen-and-ink and wash and gouache, 37.1 x 54 cm. (Box 34, Folder 645)
  - CAMPBELL, ROBERT
    - "Brackman Ker Mill. Prince of Wales Visit 13 Sept. 1919." Watercolor, 12.7 x 17.8 cm. (Box 34, Folder 646)
      Signed. Descriptive caption on mat
    - "Frontier Trading Post East, Across the Draw from the Old Church at Morley." Watercolor, 18.9 x 27.5 cm., [ca. 1920] (Box 34, Folder 647)
      Verso has watercolor of a barn. Descriptive caption on mat
    - "The Ice Harvest." Watercolor, 18 x 26.7 cm., 1920 (Box 34, Folder 648)
    - "Indian Encampment on the Ross Flats." Watercolor, 13.7 x 18.3 cm., 1920 (Box 34, Folder 649)
    - "Rainy Weather McFadsean Farm Minburn." Watercolor, 15.8 x 24.8 cm., 1925 May (Box 34, Folder 650)
    - "Stoney Indian Chief at Morley." Watercolor, 23 x 15.7 cm., 1923 (Box 34, Folder 651)
  - CAREY, ROCKWELL W.
    - [Front view of Timberline Lodge.] Lithograph, 24.2 x 31.9 cm. on sheet 30.3 x 40 cm., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 652)
      Signed. Number 18 out of 50
  - CARPENTER, F. B.
    - "The First Reading of the Emancipation Proclamation Before the Cabinet. From the Original Picture Painted at the White House in 1864." Lithograph, 64 x 91.2 cm., 1886
      "Premium engraving from The Independent"
  - CARR, EMILY
    - [Harbor scene, British Columbia, under mountains, showing barge and tug.] Watercolor, 21.1 x 25.3 cm. (Box 34, Folder 653)
      Signed "M. Carr"
    - [Native American families in boats (one canoe) in harbor.] Watercolor, visible image 18.3 x 25.9 cm., n.d. (Box 34, Folder 654)
      Signed "M. Carr." Watercolor of a bridge on verso
  - CASILEAR, GEORGE W.
    - "View of Sacramento City. As it Appeared During the Great Inundation." Engraving, 13.8 x 21.5 cm. (Box 35, Folder 655)
      "Painted by G. W. Casilear. Eng'd by W. L. Ormsby"
  - CATLIN, GEORGE
    - "Buffalo Bull, Grazing." Tinted lithograph, hand-colored, 42.4 x 58.8 cm. (Box 35, Folder 656)
      Plate no. 2. "Catlin del. on Stone by McGahey. Day & Haghe Lith."
    - "Buffalo Hunt, on Snow Shoes." Tinted lithograph, hand-colored, 42.3 x 59.1 cm. (Box 35, Folder 657)
      Plate no. 15. "Catlin del. McGahey lith. Day & Haghe Lith."
    - "Buffalo Hunt, White Wolves Attacking a Buffalo Bull." Tinted lithograph, hand-colored, 42.6 x 59.2 cm. (Box 35, Folder 658)
      Plate no. 10. "Catlin del. on Stone by McGahey. Day & Haghe Lith."
    - "Dying Buffalo Bull, in Snow Drift." Tinted lithograph, hand-colored, 42.7 x 59 cm. (Box 35, Folder 659)
      Plate no. 17. "Catlin del. McGahey lith. Day & Haghe Lith."
    - "Wounded Buffalo Bull." Tinted lithograph, hand-colored, 42.7 x 58.9 cm. (Box 35, Folder 660)
      Plate no. 16. "Catlin del. on Stone by McGahey. Day & Haghe Lith."
  - CHAPMAN, O. F.
    - [Freeport, opposite Seattle. Five frame structures on quay to left, sail boat right foreground.] Oil painting, 28.6 x 48.7 cm. in frame 41.5 x 62 cm.
  - CLAUSEN, PETER GUI
    - "Mount Tacoma." Watercolor, 20.4 x 27.2 cm. (Box 35, Folder 661)
    - "View of Lake Minnetonka seen from [Oreno?]" Watercolor, 20.4 x 27.1 cm., 1904 (Box 35, Folder 662)
    - [Waterfall.] Watercolor, 22.8 x 17.6 cm. (Box 35, Folder 663)
      Signed. "In hast [sic] 92th [sic] year 1922"
  - COLEMAN, EDMUND THOMAS
    - [Two houses on a hill, with fence around them.] Watercolor, 27.3 x 37.8 cm. (Box 35, Folder 664)
    - "Port Townsend, W.T." Watercolor, 40 x 51.7 cm., 1864 (Box 35, Folder 665)
    - Unidentified. Photograph of watercolor by Edmund T. Coleman, Lummi Indian Reservation, 20.2 x 25.5 cm. (Box 35, Folder 666)
  - COMPARET, ALEXANDER
    - [Stagecoach holdup.] Oil painting, 44.5 x 54 cm. in frame 51 x 61 cm., 1883
  - CURRIER & IVES
    - "American Homestead Autumn." Colored lithograph, 27.8 x 35.7 cm., 1869 (Box 35, Folder 667)
    - "American Homestead Winter." Lithograph, 26.7 x 37.9 cm., 1868 (Box 35, Folder 668)
    - "Catterskill Falls." Colored lithograph, 25.1 x 35.3 cm., n.d. (Box 35, Folder 669)
    - "The Hunters Shanty In the Adirondacks." Tinted lithograph, 46.4 x 60.7 cm., 1861
    - "A Midnight Race on the Mississippi." Colored lithograph, 63 x 84.5, 1860
    - "Midnight Race on the Mississippi." Colored lithograph, 30.5 x 35.4 cm., 1875 (Box 35, Folder 670)
    - "Prairie Fires of the Great West." Colored lithograph, 26.5 x 38.3 cm., 1871 (Box 35, Folder 671)
    - "A Race for the Buckhorns on the Mississippi." Colored lithograph, 63.2 x 84.5 cm., 1866
    - "Through to the Pacific." Colored lithograph, 28.1 x 35.5 cm., 1870 (Box 35, Folder 672)
  - DARLEY, FELIX OCTAVIUS CARR
    - [Hunter with three dead bears.] Etching, 29.2 x 34.6 cm., 1888 (Box 35, Folder 673)
    - "Hunting Buffaloes." Engraving, 29.2 x 34.6 cm., 1870 (Box 35, Folder 674)
      "Francis Hall, sculpt."
    - "'Put None But Americans on Guard Tonight.'" Colored lithograph, 48.3 x 35 cm., 1859 (Box 35, Folder 675)
  - DAVENPORT, HOMER
    - "A 'Tarpaulin Muster' on the San Gregorio." Pen-and-ink drawing, 27.4 x 32.9 cm. (irreg.) (Box 35, Folder 676)
    - "I gave him a slice of bread now he's happy." Pen-and-ink drawing, 72.3 x 57 cm.
      Signed. With advertisement: "Original cartoon by Homer Davenport Who Will Deliver His Famous Illustrated Lecture on The Great Arabian Desert Under the Auspices of the White Temple Wednesday Evening Jan. 15"
    - [Man, "Beef Trust" injecting "Poison" into cow, with a graveyard in background, graves marked "U.S.V."] Pen-and-ink drawing, 72.5 x 57 cm.
      Advertising bill pasted to upper right corner: "Homer Davenport America's Famous Cartoonist Will Deliver His Latest Illustrated Lecture on The Great Arabian Desert ...Jan. 15, 1908"
    - "The Snake is Fairer Than the Whiskey As He Rattles Before He Takes Your Life." Pen-and-ink drawing, 57.2 x 72.3 cm.
    - "'Substitution', or What's the difference." Pen-and-ink drawing with typescript captions pasted on, some partially missing, 72.5 x 57 cm.
  - DEMING, EDWIN WILLARD
    - [Native American chief seated on blanket, gesturing, with two women in background.] Chromolithograph, 44.1 x 34.1 cm. (Box 35, Folder 677)
  - DIXON, MAYNARD
    - [Girl riding.] Pen-and-ink heightened with white, 41.6 x 36.9 cm., 1907 (Box 35, Folder 678)
      Signed. Sketch of same two figures in different pose on verso
  - DOANE, Q. T.
    - [Country scene, with house and barn and carriage passing on the road.] Pen-and-ink and wash, 30.1 x 39.9 cm. (Box 35, Folder 679)
  - DOUGHTY, T.
    - "The Capitol. Washington, D.C. West Front from the City Hall." Lithograph, 22.5 x 29.9 cm., 1832 (Box 36, Folder 680)
      "Philadelphia, Pub. by Childs & Inman"
  - DOYLE, ALBERT E.
    - "The old Carter House - 14th & Columbia Sts. Portland, Ore." Lithograph, 19.9 x 25.7 cm. (Box 36, Folder 681)
  - DUFFY, J. A.
    - [Buffalo.] Oil painting, 30.5 x 45.8 cm. (Box 36, Folder 682)
  - DUNPHY, N. R.
    - "San Francisco Bay - Looking in through Golden Gate." Etching, plate mark 15.1 x 20.3 cm. on sheet 9.8 x 13.5 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 683)
  - E., H. D.
    - "Fort Carlton 1883. Burnt 1885 March 26." Watercolor, 17.8 x 25.3 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 684)
  - EASTMAN, H. [HARRISON?]
    - "Duck Hunting near Seabeck." Pencil sketch, 12.7 x 19.6 cm., 1874 (Box 36, Folder 685)
    - "Union City." Pencil sketch, 12.7 x 19.4 cm., 1874 (Box 36, Folder 686)
      Signed. Pencil sketch of "Seabeck" on verso
  - EASTMAN, SETH
    - "Indian Courtship." Chromolithograph, 23.1 x 15.3 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 687)
      "C. Schusessele del. Drawn by Capt. S. Eastman. Chromolith. of P.S. Duval, Pha."
    - "Falls of St. Anthony." Chromolithograph, 15.4 x 23.1 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 688)
    - "The Laughing Waters. Three Miles below the Falls of St. Anthony." Chromolithograph, 23.2 x 15.4 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 689)
    - "Marriage Custom of the Indians." Chromolithograph, 15.4 x 23.1 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 690)
    - "Sounding Wind. The Chippewa Brave." Chromolithograph, 23.1 x 15.4 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 691)
      "C. Schusessele del. Drawn by Capt. Eastman. Chromolith. of P.S. Duval, Pha."
    - "We-har-ka." Chromolithograph, 23.1 x 15.3 cm., [1852] (Box 36, Folder 692)
    - "Wenona's Leap. Lake Pepin, Miss. River." Chromolithograph, 15.3 x 23.1 cm. (Box 36, Folder 693)
  - EGGENHOFER, NICK
    - [Stagecoach.] Print, 20.7 x 27.7 cm., [1964] (Box 36, Folder 694)
      Inscribed to Stenzel by Eggenhofer, "Cody, Wyo. November 15, 1964"
  - ERB, I. J.
    - Five postcards titled: "Antelope Feeding," "Chuck Wagon - The Cow Boys Restaurant," "The 'Dry Creek Stage' - Bill Fenton, Driver," "Spooked," "Whispering Winds." Lithographs
  - ESPEY, EDWARD LINCOLN
    - [Ocean view.] Oil painting on board, 10.1 x 20.2 cm., 1872 (Box 36, Folder 695)
      "SF" written below signature
  - FARNHAM, A. M.
    - [California mission.] Lithograph, 36 x 48 cm., n.d.
      Stored in: Oversize box 59, folder 1138
  - FAY, A.
    - "Elegant Hospitality." Chromolithograph, 1854
      See: Mat for D. J. Hall watercolor, Box 37, folder 715
  - FENN, HARRY
    - [Rowboats on a lake.] Pen-and-ink and wash, 24.5 x 39.8 cm. (Box 36, Folder 696)
      Signed with initials device. "The Industrial Region of Northern Alabama, Tenn. & Ga." written on verso
  - [FERY, JOHN]
    - [Canyon scene.] Oil painting, 18 x 29.9 cm. (Box 36, Folder 697)
    - "Two Medicine Lake, Glacier Park." Oil painting, 14.7 x 24.1 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 698)
  - FLAGG, JAMES MONTGOMERY
    - "'Come, let's make the best of it & cheat the gossip." Pen-and-ink drawing, 54.7 x 75 cm.
  - FORD, HENRY CHAPMAN
    - [Spanish mission house.] Etching, 19.7 x 27.8 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 699)
  - FRIEND, WASHINGTON
    - "Niagara River Looking Towards Lake Ontario." Color print, 9.3 x 14.8 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 700)
  - FRIES, ALBERT
    - "The U.S. Ship 'New York.'" Lithograph, 24.5 x 60.1 cm., 1895
  - GAY, M. O.
    - [Battleship Oregon.] Watercolor, 29.8 x 22.5 cm., 1905 (Box 36, Folder 701)
      Title from Stenzel's note
  - GEORGE STINSON & CO.
    - "In Remembrance of the One Hundredth Anniversary of the United States." Tinted lithograph, 76 x 58.2 cm., 1876
      Stored in: Oversize box 59, folder 1141
  - GIFFORD, ROBERT SWAIN
    - "Mount Hood, from the Columbia." Steel engraving, 29.3 x 31.5 cm., 1874 (Box 36, Folder 702)
  - GILBERT, ARTHUR HILL
    - "Near Sierra City." Oil painting, 22.6 x 30.6 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 703)
  - GILBERT, ROMEO MONROE
    - [Camping Wilhoit Springs.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 17.7 x 22.7 cm. (Box 36, Folder 704)
  - GOLLINGS, ELLING WILLIAM
    - "Packing." Etching, 20.1 x 27.6 cm., 1927 (Box 36, Folder 705)
    - "Sentinels." Etching, 27.4 x 32.7 cm., n.d. (Box 36, Folder 706)
  - GOODWIN, PHILIP R.
    - [Native American extending hand.] Pen-and-ink and pastel, 8.2 x 13.2 cm. (Box 37, Folder 707)
      Signed. Holograph note below image: "How Jim! Happy New Year."
  - GRAHAM, C.
    - See also C. Graham's artwork in Series V, in box 49, folders 974 and 977
    - "Niagara Falls from Michigan Central Train." Chromolithograph, 48 x 71.2 cm., 1903
      "American Lithographic Co., N.Y."
  - GREEN, E.
    - "Mount Hood." Pencil drawing, 29.2 x 46.9 cm., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 708)
  - GRISET, ERNEST HENRY
    - [Eagle.] Charcoal and watercolor, 54.6 x 44.1 cm. (Box 37, Folder 709)
  - GROLL, ALBERT LOREY
    - "Virginia City - Nevada." Pencil drawing, 8.3 x 14 cm., 1914 Oct 4 (Box 37, Folder 710)
      Front of postcard to "Joe"
  - GUSTIN, PAUL MORGAN
    - "Halibut Boats." Etching, plate mark 18.7 x 22.6 cm on sheet 21.5 x 24.6 cm., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 711)
    - [Large sailing ships.] Etching, plate mark 14.5 x 18.5 cm. on sheet 24.8 x 33.6 cm., 1927 (Box 37, Folder 712)
    - "Long Ago." Etching, plate mark 14.9 x 18.6 cm. on sheet 19.8 x 26.2 cm., 1921 (Box 37, Folder 713)
    - "Ships Stores." Etching, plate mark 14.6 x 18.3 cm. on sheet 28.4 x 31.7 cm. (Box 37, Folder 714)
      Signed. "2/2 First State on Japan"
  - HALL, D. J.
    - "Shilshole Bay near Ft. Lawton." Watercolor, 25 x 30.1 cm., 1880 (Box 37, Folder 715)
      Signed. Bottom of mat has 3/4 of a lithograph pasted to it: "Elegant Hospitality" by A. Fay, 1854
  - HANCOCK, C.
    - "Queen of Trumps. Winner of the Great St. Leger Stakes at Doncaster 1835; Rode by T. Lye." Engraving, 36.8 x 49.5 cm. (Box 37, Folder 716)
      "London published...by R. Ackermann"
  - HANDFORTH, THOMAS SCHOFIELD
    - [Three men sitting on logs.] Etching, plate mark 14.7 x 16 cm. on sheet 22.5 x 28 cm., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 717)
  - HANSEN, H. W. (HERMANN WENDELBORG)
    - "The Last of the Maine and Her Men." Chromolithograph, 66.5 x 99 cm., 1898
      "H.S. Crocker Co. Lith. S.F."
  - HAYES, [WILLIAM P.]
    - [Farm scene.] Charcoal drawing, 29.1 x 34.5 cm., 1927 (Box 37, Folder 718)
    - [House with fire hydrant in front.] Crayon, 30.1 x 22.6 cm., 1953 (Box 37, Folder 719)
    - [House with turret.] Colored pencil, 24.3 x 22.3 cm., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 720)
    - [Industrial building with smoke coming out of smokestacks.] Charcoal drawing, 23.3 x 30.5 cm., 1928 (Box 37, Folder 721)
    - [Mill scene.] Charcoal drawing, 23.2 x 31.1 cm., 1929 (Box 37, Folder 722)
    - [Scene with tree in foreground, buildings in background.] Watercolor, 21.9 x 29.9 cm., [1952?] (Box 37, Folder 723)
    - [View of bridge from below.] Charcoal drawing, 23.3 x 31 cm., 1925 (Box 37, Folder 724)
    - "Winter - Grant Street." Oil painting, 37 x 48.5 cm. in frame 51 x 61.5 cm., n.d.
  - HEANEY, CHARLES EDWARD
    - "Silver Mountain." Linoleum block print, 15.6 x 20.8 cm., [1936] (Box 37, Folder 725)
      Signed. "ED 25. To F. W. Skiff May 4 1936"
  - [HERNE, H.?]
    - [Logging scene.] Print on silk, 27.4 x 36.3 cm., n.d. (Box 37, Folder 726)
  - HILL, EDWARD RUFUS
    - "Hood River." Pencil drawing, 15.2 x 22.8 cm., 1914 Oct (Box 37, Folder 727)
  - HOLLOWAY, [----?]
    - "The Niagara Railway Suspension Bridge 1859." Chromolithograph, 35.1 x 50.6 cm. (Box 37, Folder 728)
      "Holloway Del. Lith. of Endicott & Co. N.Y." Published by W. O. Buchanan
  - HOUGHTON, MERRITT DANA
    - [Logging camp in Laramie, Wyo.] Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, 26.5 x 52 cm.
    - "Tatham Ranch, Big Laramie River." Pen-and-ink and watercolor, 26.5 x 52 cm.
  - HUDSON, GRACE CARPENTER
    - [Little Mendicino.] Oil painting on stretcher, 23 x 18 cm.
  - HUTCHINS, ERNEST
    - "Bow Range Near Banff, Rockies." Watercolor, 29.8 x 35.4 cm., 1911 (Box 37, Folder 729)
  - INNES, JOHN W.
    - [Five untitled etchings of cowboys and their horses.] 24.8 x 35.2 cm. on sheet 29.7 x 43.7 cm. and smaller, 1900 (Box 37, Folder 730)
  - J., H.
    - "Fort Bellingham, Bellingham Bay, Whatcom Co., Wash." Two pencil drawings on one sheet, 25.4 x 18.8 cm., 1899 Jan (Box 38, Folder 731)
  - JACKSON, WILLIAM HENRY
    - "Birth of Oregon - Champoeg, May 2, 1843." Watercolor and pastel, visible image 20.4 x 32.1 cm., 1941 Jul (Box 38, Folder 732)
      Signed. Inscribed by Jackson on verso. With note: "Presented to Walter Meacham of Portland, Ore - a friend of Mr. W. H. Jackson's and purchased from Mr. Meacham's widow in 1951"
  - JAMES, WILL
    - [Cowboy roping a steer.] Etching, plate mark 15.2 x 20.2 cm. on sheet 22.3 x 30.3 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 733)
      "Etching by Will James. Printed by Hans Kleiber"
    - [Cowboy sketches.] Etching, plate mark 12.6 x 10 cm. on sheet 21 x 16 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 734)
      "Etchings by Will James. Printed by Hans Kleiber."
  - JOHNSON, E. R.
    - "Simla." Watercolor, 16 x 22 cm. on sheet 25.2 x 35.9 cm., 1871 (Box 38, Folder 735)
  - JUDSON, WILLIAM LEES
    - "Arroyo Seco." Watercolor, 33.6 x 51.2 cm. (Box 38, Folder 736)
    - "Pasadena Ave [rest of caption illegible]" Watercolor, 43 x 56.4 cm., 1894 (Box 38, Folder 737)
  - JUKES, ED [?]
    - "Whalam Bay." Watercolor, 13.5 x 22.7 cm. (Box 38, Folder 738)
  - KEGG, GEORGE W.
    - "On the Santa Fe." Etching, plate mark 9.4 x 15.8 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 739)
  - KELLER, PAUL
    - [Industrial dockyard scene.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 29.9 x 40.7 cm. (Box 38, Folder 740)
  - KELLY, I. V.
    - "Ambulance, built at the Gov. Repair Shops, Washington D.C. under the direction of Brevet Major General D. U. Rucker, Quartermaster, U.S. Army." Pen-and-ink drawing, 25.1 x 23.2 cm. (Box 38, Folder 741)
  - KEMBLE, EDWARD WINSOR
    - [Uncle Sam's wards.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 26.4 x 19.6 cm., n.y. Mar 20 (Box 38, Folder 742)
  - KNOWLES, JOE
    - [Bear looking over valley.] Oil painting on stretcher, 54.5 x 68.3 cm., 1920
    - "The Flying Dutchman." Drypoint etching, plate mark 29.6 x 22.5 cm. on sheet 33.4 x 25.2 cm. (Box 38, Folder 743)
      No. 140 of first edition
    - "Ilwacs Fishing Wharf." Etching, plate mark 11.4 x 15 cm. on sheet 22.5 x 30.4 cm. (Box 38, Folder 744)
      No. 12 of 100
    - "Port Dock." Etching, plate mark 14.9 x 22.8 cm. on sheet 18.7 x 25.6 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 745)
  - KOLLNER, AUGUSTUS B.
    - "Col. Cody." Etching, plate mark 11.3 x 14.7 cm. on sheet 20 x 29.9 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 746)
  - KURZ & ALLISON
    - "Battle of Atlanta." Chromolithograph, 50.5 x 70 cm., 1888
    - "Battle of Bull Run." Chromolithograph, 50.6 x 70 cm., 1889
    - "Battle of Champion-Hills." Chromolithograph, 50 x 68 cm., 1887
    - "Battle of Spotsylvania." Chromolithograph, 50.2 x 66 cm., 1888
    - "Battle of Stone River. Near Murfreesborough, Tenn." Chromolithograph, 63.7 x 67 cm., 1891
    - "Surrender of Admiral Cervera July 3d, 1898. On board the Battleship Iowa." Chromolithograph, 53.2 x 71 cm.
      Stored in: Oversize box 60, folder 1147
  - [L., O.?]
    - [Empty wood frame carved with an eagle at top with the dates 1835 and 1888 on either side. At bottom the word "Beaver" is carved within a scroll] 29.5 x 32.3 cm.
      Partially removed paper pasted to back of frame has the words "carved by O. L."
  - L. PRANG & CO.
    - See also: Thomas Moran, box 40, folders 771-783
    - "Grant from West Point to Appomattox." Chromolithograph, 59.9 x 45.6 cm., 1885 (Box 38, Folder 747)
  - [LANGER, JOSEPH]
    - [Gold mining scene.] Etching, 30.4 x 45.6 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 748)
      "After E. Narjot"
  - LARAY, EMIL
    - "Camp Warner Oregon 1873. Garrisoned by Co. 'D' 21st Infy." Watercolor, 33.5 x 45.6 cm. (Box 38, Folder 749)
  - LAZARUS, EDGAR M.
    - [City scene.] Lithograph, 25.3 x 20.3 cm. (Box 38, Folder 750)
  - LEE, MANNING DE VILLANEUVE
    - "His cutlass broke against mine and fell in pieces at his feet." Oil painting, 90 x 60 cm. in frame 98 x 68 cm., [1925]
      Illustration for The Sword of the House of De Marillac. Attribution of artist from Sotheby's auction catalog June 24, 1980: Fine American Western Paintings: The Collection of Dr. and Mrs. Franz Stenzel
  - LEIGHTON, A. C.
    - "Bow Lakes." Color print on front of notecard, 14.8 x 18.2 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 751)
    - "Emerald Lake." Color print on front of notecard, 14.6 x 17.9 cm., n.d.
    - "Lake Louise." Color print on front of notecard, 14.6 x 18 cm., n.d.
    - "Magog Lake and Glacier." Color print on front of notecard, 14.5 x 18 cm.
  - LEWIS, E.
    - "Off Esquimalt." Watercolor, 17.4 x 27.6 cm., n.d. (Box 38, Folder 752)
  - LOCHRIE, ELIZABETH DAVEY
    - [Portrait of a little girl.] Watercolor[?], 19.1 x 15.2 cm., 1966 (Box 38, Folder 753)
  - M., M. C.
    - Native Americans of the Pacific Northwest. Seven watercolor portraits, 28.9 x 23.2 cm. and smaller (Box 39, Folder 754-760)
  - MACDONALD, "PAY-YOUR-DEBTS"
    - "Harry Murphy from Life." Pen-and-ink drawing, 27.8 x 22.8 cm., 1905 (Box 39, Folder 761)
  - MAGELSSEN, NELL
    - [Cowboy on bucking horse.] Pen-and-ink drawing, 25.4 x 19.7 cm. (Box 39, Folder 762)
  - MANHATTAN ART COMPANY
    - "Battle of Gettysburg." Color print, visible image 39 x 56.2 cm., 1893
      "Printed by Paul Philippotpaux"
    - "Washington Centennial Souvenir. Washington Entering New York, and the Portraits of the Presidents of the United States." Tinted lithograph, 56.5 x 70.1 cm., 1889
  - MARTIN, J. H.
    - [Three Native Americans in front of tipis.] Watercolor, 18.9 x 24.9 cm., n.d. (Box 39, Folder 763)
  - MARTIN, THOMAS MOWER
    - [The artist and his guide in western Canada.] Watercolor, 26 x 56.1 cm.
    - "Coast of Vancouver Island." Watercolor, 14.1 x 19.5 cm. (Box 39, Folder 764)
    - "W. Coast B.C." Watercolor, 17 x 33.4 cm. (Box 39, Folder 765)
  - MEISSNER, [----?]